phionbalance.com 2011-06-03

# Privacy Policy of pHion, Scottsdale (AZ)

## Your Privacy

Last Updated: August 31, 2010

Our commitment to privacy is straight-forward: Your personal information is your personal and private property. We never sell or share your information with third-party marketers unless you explicitly instruct us to do so. To demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we work with TRUSTe to have them audit our Web site and e-mail applications, while they are not done yet we will update the site when the final results are in. In addition, every one of our employees is required to sign a Privacy Pledge upon starting a new job with us.

### Scope and Changes

Apex Wellness Group, LLC., dba pHion Balance ("pHion Balance", "essential pH" or "we") operates the websites, [www.ph-ion.com](http://www.ph-ion.com/), [www.phionbalance.com](http://www.phionbalance.com/), [www.essentialph.com](http://www.essentialph.com/), and various other related sites that refer to this Website Privacy Statement in a direct hyperlink (the "Websites"). pHion Balance respects your privacy and we want you to be confident in sharing your information with us. This Website Privacy Statement is designed to inform you of the types of information we collect from users, how we use that information, and the circumstances under which we will share it with third parties. This Privacy Statement applies only to the Websites. It does not apply to your use of any other websites (whether or not operated by us), including any websites which we provide links to or websites of our partners or advertisers, or to any activities which are not online.

Please note that some features and/or services referenced may not be available on some Websites. Therefore, portions of this Privacy Statement which pertain to such features or services may not be applicable on each of the Websites.

pHion Balance is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because pHion Balance wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices governing the Websites reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

This Privacy Statement is effective as of the date listed above. Even if you read and/or agreed to a prior policy statement, you need to review this updated version. We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Statement at any time and at our discretion. If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes to this Privacy Statement accessible on the homepage of the Websites, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via either email or by posting a notice on the Websites for 30 days.

### Personal Information and How We Use It

Generally it is possible to use the Websites without providing us with any personally identifiable information, but on some of our Websites, users have the option of providing various types of personal information to make the best use of available services and features. This section describes what we collect and how we use it. Providing the information is always voluntary, however, and you can always choose not to provide the information by choosing not to use the service or feature. By providing the information you agree to our use consistent with this statement.

**Information Submitted By You**

**Zip Code Only:** On some of the Websites, you have the choice of providing your ZIP Code. We use your ZIP Code to compute actual pricing including the cost of shipping and sales tax.

**E-mail Address Only:** On some of the Websites if you wish to sign up as a registered user, register for Alerts or any one of our Newsletters, provide reviews, and/or participate in forum discussions, we require that you provide us with your email address. We will use this to email you the related information you have requested.

**Basic Contact Info:** On some of the Websites a user is able to become a registered user. When a user decides to become a registered user, we ask for some basic contact information, such as username, ZIP Codes, and email address. We use this basic contact information to facilitate the use of certain features of our Websites (e.g., product reviews) and to send you information about our company, services and products, and to communicate occasional offers.

**Complete Contact Info:** When a user wishes to purchase an item directly through one of our Websites, we collect full name, e-mail address, phone number(s), shipping/billing address related credit card information. All credit card information is encrypted.

On some of the Websites a registered user may decide to become a business partner. When registering as a business partner, we collect complete contact information, i.e., full name, address, e-mail address, and phone number, and in some instances a credit card number and expiration date. We use this information to validate the business partner’s identity and in some instances to bill for products ordered from pHion Balance. All credit card information is encrypted.

**Service User Information:** On the Websites where it is available, if a user wants to receive information about how our products perform for a specific lifestyle or condition, pHion requests that users of certain Website services complete a questionnaire, which includes personal and contact information ("Service User Information"). Service User Information enables pHion Balance to provide Service Users with information specifically about requested products and services.

**Content or Correspondence Submitted By You:** When a user chooses to post content on any of the Websites where posting is available, for example, in the form of a product review, or submits personal correspondence to pHion Balance, we may collect and maintain that information in a file specific to the user.

**Information Acquired Automatically**

We collect certain information on the Websites through the user's experience and activities, cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that detail their viewing preferences, activities and interactions with pHion Balance. Consequently, collected information is tied to the user's personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to the Websites, and, subject to the Opt-Out Policy stated below, to direct pertinent marketing promotions and communications to them.

**Cookies:** A cookie is a piece of data tied to information about the user and stored on the user's computer. We use both session cookies, which terminate when a user closes his browser, and persistent cookies, which remain on the user's computer until manually deleted. Cookies are used to help make your use of our Websites more enjoyable. pHion Balance creates these cookie files on your hard drive through your browser and uses them to save information on your pHion Balance username, ZIP Codes and Website preferences so you can avoid re-entry of this information each time you visit our Websites. Cookies also help us to deliver content specific to your interests. You may decline our cookies if your web browser software permits, although this may prevent you from accessing certain features on our Websites.

**Log Files:** Like most standard website servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the Web site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We use your IP address at times to help identify you as you browse and to gather broad technical and demographic information on who uses our Websites. We do not tie log files to personally identifiable information.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs):** We employ and/or our third party advertisers employ a software technology called clear gifs (also known as Web Beacons or Web Bugs). They help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content and which campaigns are effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics, about the size of a period at the end of a sentence, with a unique identifier. Clear gifs are similar in function to cookies and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In addition, pHion Balance and its advertisers may use clear gifs in HTML-based emails. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns by showing how many emails recipients have opened. We do not tie web-beacons to personally identifiable information.

**General Uses Of Information**

In addition to the uses described above, we may use your personal information for any of the following:

To contact you in response to a customer service question from you, or in relation to any issue arising in respect of the agreement between pHion Balance and you, or to resolve or attempt to resolve a dispute between users or between pHion Balance and you.

To process credit card payments approved in advance by you.

To allow you to send an email to another user through the Send To A Friend feature on our Websites, where available.

To assist law enforcement or other governmental agencies investigating cases of possible illegal activities by third parties.

To improve the experience of using the Websites, improve pHion’s products and services, improve marketing and promotion of our products and services, customize the Websites' content and layout, and generally improve the Websites to meet your needs better.

### Who We Share Your Personal Information With

**Aggregated information:** We aggregate personal information into statistics about users, their usage of the Websites, traffic patterns, and demographics. We may provide third parties with such statistics, but never in a way that would make the information personally identifiable: this data is aggregated from millions of users to the Websites each month.

**Processing Agents:** We may from time to time use external service providers to facilitate or outsource elements of our service or operation of the Websites, including without limitation the use of agencies to process credit card transactions.

**Business Transfer:** As we continue to develop our business we might buy or sell companies, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information is generally one of the transferred assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing privacy policy. In the event that our company, or substantially all of its assets, is acquired, your information may be one of the transferred assets and we may share it with an actual or potential acquirer.

**Legal Requests and Customers' Requests:** We cooperate with law enforcement inquiries and third parties to enforce all applicable laws including but not limited to laws relating to intellectual property rights, fraud, and other rights. Therefore, we can (and you authorize us to) release your name, city, state, telephone number, email address, previous fraud complaints, if any, and other account and personal information without a subpoena, court order or other substantially similar legal procedure to law enforcement entities when we believe release is necessary to comply with the law to protect the rights, property, or integrity of the Websites, our customers, users or third parties, or to prevent illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threat to the physical safety of any person, or violation of pHion’s Terms of Use. Further we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your name, street address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, email, and company name to consumers who have alleged fraud or any other consumer dispute relating to their transactions and/or communications with you.

**Other Trusted Parties:** We may provide your contact information and other personal data to trusted third parties to provide information on products and services that may be of interest to you.

### Accessing and Changing your Personal Information

For registered users on some of the Websites, a user can review personal identifiable information by logging in with the user email and password and then clicking on the "My Account" link located on each page. After accessing the user's My Account page, click the appropriate link under the Account Information section to make changes as necessary.

For access and changes of any other data, please contact us. Upon receipt of your request, and possibly subject to identification measures, we will provide you with reasonable access and comply with appropriate data correction requests in accordance with applicable law. For access requests, we will respond within thirty (30) days upon receiving your request.

You should also note that if we have provided your information to third parties, you will have to make a separate request to them directly if you want to have your information removed from, or corrected in, their databases.

### Third Party Advertising and Links to Third Party Websites

Third parties displaying advertisements on our Websites may also use cookies or clear gifs which are activated when you click on those advertisements. pHion does not control the use of cookies and clear gifs by third parties. The use of cookies and clear gifs by these companies is subject to their own privacy policies, which you may review by visiting their websites.

### Choice/Opt-out Policy

We understand you may not want to receive email from us. You can choose to opt-out of receiving email communications from us by selecting to opt out if and when you register on our Websites, by following the unsubscribe instructions in the email communication we send you during your initial account creation process.

To opt out of receiving all other pHion mailings after you have registered, click here or click the appropriate unsubscribe link contained within the email that you receive. Please note that opting out may prevent you from receiving email from pHion regarding updates and improvements to the Websites or offers and promotions we may be offering.

### Your California Privacy Rights

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits residents of California who are registered users and use our service for private, family or household purposes to request certain standard information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes (including a list of categories of data disclosed in the previous calendar year and names and addresses of data recipients). To make such a request, please contact us as provided below.

### Internet Crime Complaint Center

pHion Balance wants your Internet surfing experience to be safe. Help protect yourself. If you believe you have been a victim of Internet crime you can file a complaint with the Internet Crime Complaint Center (IC3), a partnership between the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and the National White Collar Crime Center. Their website is <http://www.ic3.gov/>

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Website, or your use of the Website, please contact us at

**pHion Balance**  
Attn: Privacy Matters  
14362 N Frank Lloyd Wright Blvd., Suite 1000  
Scottsdale, AZ 85260  

If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with pHion Balance to resolve users concerns.
